Hey [ __ ], Saturday is here again and I have
also come in front of you with my next
video which is a very important
topic for all of you.  fox Whenever a
new health insurance plan is
launched in the market and the insurance companies are
claiming that it is a revolutionary
health insurance plan and there is no
health insurance plan like it in the market, then it becomes
very important to compare such plans because without
comparison we cannot know how much
truth is there in the claims of the insurance company and there are some rules and regulations for comparison also.
No plan can be compared with any other plan.
We can compare it with the plans having similar features.  Of course
you understand which
plan I am talking about.  I am
talking about the recent Reshore 3.0 plan of Latch Niva Bupa.  The
insurance company claims
that such a plan is not available in the market.   Let's
see how much truth there is in his claim.
Is it true that such a plan is not available in the market
or is their claim just hollow?  So
you will watch this video till the end.
Share it with your friends and relatives also.
If you have come to Insurance Service for the first time,
then subscribe to Insurance Service and
also press the bell icon.
[Music]
So let's start today's
video with a little introduction.
My name is Sandeep Singhal.  I am a business
entrepreneur and
cofounder of InsuranceSeva.com.  I have been selling insurance products for the last 20 years.
We also provide you insurance claim service.  If you
want to purchase insurance products through us,
you can also call us on the number given on the screen.
So let's start the
comparison video now Neevapa 3.0 ICC LBD
Elevate Plan, Medior Salad Plan from Tata AIG,
Superstar Star Health plan
and along with it,
Ultimate Care Plan from Care Health Insurance.  I have taken all these five
plans because the
features of all these five plans are similar to each other.
So what remains to be seen is that what Nivapa
is claiming is that Shore 3.0 has
all those features which are not available in any other plan.
So let us see whether they
are within these plans and if they are within the plans
then what is their pricing.
Before starting the video, first of all I will
talk about the fundamentals of an insurance company.  No matter
how much the insurance company
claims that their plan
is revolutionary, unlimited, this is there, that is there.  But the
truth about the insurance company becomes clear
when you go to make a claim.  So, to get a hassle-
free claim, it is
very important to check the fundamentals of the insurance company.
All the features are secondary.  So first of all let us
talk about
what the claim settlement ratio of these insurance companies
says?  So first of all Neevapa 92% ICC
LBD 97% Tata AIG 95% Star Health 82%
and Care Health Insurance 93%
Now let's talk about what the Incred Claim Ratio
says as I have already told you.
Incred Claim Ratio
means how much total premium you have received
and
how many claims you have paid against that premium.  This is
called incurred claims ratio.  Suppose
you took a premium of ₹100 and
against that you made claims of ₹80, then
your incurred claim ratio is 80%.  Nivapa
with 59% incurred claim ratio ICB 79%
Tata AIG 78% 66% Star Health and Care 58%
Health Insurance Solvency Ratio
i.e.
how much money and assets do you have against total liabilities?
Niva Bupa's is ₹2.55, which means
they have ₹255 against ₹100.  The solvency ratio of IC
Silamba is 2.68, Tata AIIG is 2.09, Star Health is 2.21
and Care Health Insurance is 1.74.  Let's look at the
network hospitals.
That is, which
hospitals do they have for cashless treatment?  So
Neev Bupa has 11,000 hospitals, ICC LBD
has 15,000 hospitals, Tata AIG has 14,000 hospitals,
Star Health has 9.400
hospitals and Care Health Insurance has 9.400 hospitals.
So let us talk about the reimbursement claim
process.  So the reimbursement claim process of Niva BPA ICC LB Tata
AIG and Care Health Insurance
is fully online.  They have apps, they have links, on which
you will go and upload your documents step by step,
then your
claim will be settled.  But here
Star Health is fully offline.  Here
you have to submit all the physical documents in their office.
So let us start this
comparison and first of all we will talk about
those features which
insurance companies are claiming to be revolutionary and
unique.
Talking about Neevapa 3.0, Neevapa says
that you will get unlimited sum assured under this plan.
I'm not talking about unlimited
restoration or unlimited cumulative bonuses here.  The
sum assured
is unlimited and they have no other option.  There
is only one option Unlimited Sum
Assured.  So is there any
plan available to compare it?  Yes, it is available.
Elevate plan of ICIC LBD where
one of the options of sum assured is unlimited
sum assured.  All we
can say is that the exclusive unlimited sum
assured policy is Niva Reshore 3.0.
So we have two of these five plans
that have unlimited sums assured.  Nibup
resh 3.0 and the second is ICC LBA's Elevate
Plan.  Talking about other features,
Neevapar 3.0 is providing cover for 145 diseases from day one.
You can see the list on my screen
because I cannot name all these diseases.  It will take a
lot of time.   The
entire video will be played in this.
In comparison, ICC Lombard is providing cover for five diseases
from 31 days, which is
called jump start.  Hypertension, diabetes,
obesity, asthma and hyperlipidemia.
Same as Tata AIG Select Plan, there
also they are giving cover of five diseases i.e. cover of A B
C D from 31 days.
Talking about the ultimate care of the star superstar,
there he is covering a heart
disease i.e. a stunt from
day one.  Along with all these
diseases, if we compare it, then
Neev Ratio 3.0 has given surprise benefit. If you
buy the policy and download its app, you will
get some surprise or the other and whatever surprise you get will be
related to health care service only. ICC
Lombard has Power Booster, every year
your sum assured will accumulate for life
time which beats inflation. It is an
add on cover, if you want you can add it,
you will have to pay a little amount of money. It will
give additional super charge bonus of the premium. Tata AIG's Select plan will
accumulate up to five times your time.
If you take this add on cover, then there
is Superstar Bonus and Infinity Bonus. Star
Health has Superstar Bonus and Care
Health Insurance's Ultimate Care has
Infinity Bonus.  In both of these, your
sum assured will keep
accumulating for life.  This is also a good add
on cover.  So in the comparison here,
this
benefit is available in almost all the policies.  And if I talk about
Tata IG, then it will
go up to five times only.
In all other companies, this will keep accumulating for you all your life.
But there is no need for this in Neeba
because they have made the time limit
unlimited.  Lock the clock
facility is available in only two plans.  With entry into Neevapa
Reshore 3.0 and Star Health's
Superstar Plan, your
age will be locked and
your premium will not increase until you make a claim.  The
age band is still going to increase according to inflation.
Nivapa
has four variants available.  Classic
Select Elite and Black.  You will get this benefit
only in light and black.  If
I talk about Classic and Select, then
Lock the Clock is not available there.
OPD cover is provided by Neevashar 3.0. OPD
means you can
avail OPD benefits up to five times the premium you pay.
1x, 2x, 3x and 5x means it is your
choice as to how many x OPD
benefits you want to avail.  The same amount of premium will have to be paid additionally.  It will
also be available on cashless basis and
on reimbursement basis, you will
get OPD cover with co-pay payment, which
also includes pharmacy cover and diagnostic
cover, many other benefits have been added to it.  There is
cashback which they had earlier
in Aspire.  Points accumulate at the rate of 10% of the premium you pay.
You can use them to pay a premium
, pay a copay, or
pay a deductible.
He has given Neevapa forest.
This is a kind of membership in Neevapa Forest.  If you
add this, your claim will be
settled on a little priority and
you will get many similar benefits in Neevapa roses 3.0.
He has provided the cover of Borderless.  That means go outside India and get
treatment.  There are two
options for specific illnesses, that is,
you can avail this benefit for some critical illnesses or you
can avail it for all illnesses.  You can choose from 0% payment
to 50% payment.
You have a choice.  There is an additional feature.
Talking about ICC LB, Infinite Care
in Tata AG Select Infinite Advantage
Limitless Cover Superstar means you can
take unlimited claim once in your lifetime.
You will decide when to take it.
This is an add on feature.  Hospitalization will be for 2 hours.  This will
also be the case in Reshore 3.0 and ICC
Lombard's Elevate plan, where the
minimum hospitalization condition will be 2 hours.
Unlimited Restoration Same Person
Same Illness will be available in all four policies except
Accept Neev now above Rashored 3.0 because
there the sum assured itself is unlimited.  However,
unlimited restoration same person same illness has
now become a basic feature of any health insurance plan.
Now no plan is launched without this feature.
Because this is a feature which has now become a necessity in
today's time.  Now let's talk about some discounts
also.  So under Rs 3.0
you will get a discount of 2.5% on renewal.
If you renew 30 days in advance.
You will get the same discount in Tata also.  Will
also be in Superstar.  If you
renew your renewal 30 days in advance.
You are going to get this benefit in ICC LB also.
You will get Young Family Discount in Tata AIG and
you can also get up to 10% discount in Niva UPSO 3.0.  The
superstar has given the future shield.  That means, if you add this add-on
and you are an individual, that is,
you are young, unmarried and you get married, then
your spouse will be
added immediately and all his/her
waiting periods will be waived, including the
initial waiting period and the two-year
waiting period.  Apart from that, if I
talk about the waiting period of PED, then Niva
Bupa has the option to reduce it.
Apart from 145 diseases, you
can also reduce your PED cover for up to one year.  You can
reduce it even after 2 years.  And the
same option
is also available in Ultimate Care of your Care Health Insurance.
Care Health
Insurance's Ultimate Care Plan offers a tenure multiplier.
If you take a policy for 3 years or 4 years,
you will get 3 years of time cover from
day one itself.  This is a very nice
feature.  This feature is not available in Booba's Aspire
plan.  This feature is not available in Reard 3.0.
Apart from that, if we talk about loyalty boost, there
is a loyalty boost
in Ultimate Care of Care Health Insurance.  This means that whatever
time is assured for you will be doubled.  If
you do not make any claim for 7 years.  There
is another feature here.  And that feature is called
Premium Payback.  In Ultimate Care,
if you do not make a claim for 5 years, then the
first year's premium will be returned to you
i.e. it will be refunded.
So now let's come to the basic features, what are the
general basic features that are inside Plus
saying.  So if we
talk about sum assured, it is unlimited in Reshore 3.0
and there is no problem.  ICICI LBA
starts from Rs 5 lakh and goes up to unlimited.
In Tata EIG, time options ranging from ₹5 lakh to ₹
crore
are available to you.  Options ranging from ₹10 lakh to ₹1
crore are available in Superstar.  Options are available within K with
time horizon ranging from ₹5 lakh to ₹1 crore.
Apart from time, options have also started to
matter to you because inflation has
increased a lot.  Inflation is increasing.  So it becomes
very important to take a reasonable time.
Talking about the entry age, now there is
no maximum entry age in any of these plans.  The minimum age is 18 years
but now anyone of any age can
enter the policy.  The policy
tenure will be 5 years.  Niva Upshor 3.0 has a
5-year tenure in the Elevate plan
and a 5-year tenure
in Superstar and Ultimate Care.  Tataij has
options available for only 3 years.
Talking about variants, I have already
told you that in NIV above rhsur 3.0
you have four variants available - Classic Select Black and
Elite.  And Tata
AIG has two variants.  Premier and
Lite are not variants in other plans.
A single plan is available.  Family
Size Two Adult Four Kid Reshore 3.0 Ho Two
Adult Three Kid Elevate Two Adult Three Kid
Select Plan Two Adult Four Kid Superstar
Two Adult Two Kid Ultimate Care Plan.  So
these are all family size.  This means that if
you have more than two children, then
Ultimate Care will not work for you.  If you have
more than three children then you do
not have to take Lombard's Elevate plan.  I
also want to buy Tata LG Medic Select.  So you have only two
options.  Either you have to go to Ratio 3.0
or you have to go to Superstar.  Let's
talk about room rent.
One very important point or I can say most
important point is room rent capping
for health insurance policy.  Because all the
expenses are linked to the hospital room rent.
As soon as you change the room category,
all the expenses will change.  So,
if you buy the lower variant of Riyesh and 3.0, whether
you buy Classic or Elite, then there will be a
cap on the room rent.   In
Classic you will get only General Ward
and in Select you will get Twin Sharing
Ward.  I don't know what the insurance company's
philosophy is behind this.  What are you thinking?
But my own thinking says that
if a person is buying health insurance
then why would he stay in a general ward
or take a twin sharing room?  At
least you will have to take a single private AC room.
So for these two variants,
I would strictly tell you not to
go for this.  If you want to get Ryush and 3.0, then at
least Elite or Black.  By looking at the remaining premiums you will
know what their premiums mean.
Talking about HC
Lombard, there is an inbuilt single
private AC room.  You
can both upgrade and downgrade it.  It will be your choice.
Tata
AG's Medic Select plan will offer a single private AC room.  Any Room and
Any Category Room will be in Superstar and Ultimate
Care.  Payment is not in any plan.
ICU, ICCU up to some
is assured.  Now let's talk about day care
treatment, it is covered in all the policies.
Up to some assured.  We will talk about modern treatment.  It
is very important in today's date.
Maximum surgeries are robotic.
Many treatments are modern.
Because by taking modern treatment,
healing happens very quickly and blood loss
etc. is very less.  An advanced
treatment technology has come
into the market.  So, there is a capping of ₹1 lakh on Classic and Select,
so the plan becomes useless.
So if you want to buy it then you have to
buy Elite or Black.
I could
not understand the logic behind making these two plans.  There is no capping on modern treatment robotic surgeries in the remaining four plans
and there is no capping on Elite and Black in 3.0 also.  There are a
lot of pre-hospitalization and post-hospitalization expenses
before going to the hospital and even more
expenses are incurred after coming back from the hospital.
If there is a critical illness, then
in cancer cases, I have even seen that the
patient has to take tablets and capsules worth Rs. 5-10 lakhs regularly.
I have a client, Jain sir.  His wife has
cancer.  There are multiple cancers.  So
she takes medicines worth Rs 5 to 6 lakh every month.
Which are post hospitalization expenses.  So this
is a very important part.  60 Days 180 Days Niva Bupa 90 Days 180
Days Elevate.  Here's where Elevate comes up
that they've also made the pre 90.  90
Days and 90 Days Select Plan 90 and 180
Superstar 60 and 90 There may be some compromise here.  It becomes the
ultimate care plan.  E-consultation
is covered in all policies.  ICC
except Labrador and is covered unlimited.  There
is no capping of any kind.  But in Ultimate Care,
online consultation can be taken only from general physicians.
I have already told you about restoration.  If we
talk about ambulance, road ambulance is up to sum
assured cover in all the policies
but in Niva Bupa Select and Classic
you will get a cap of ₹2000 and air
ambulance will not be available.
Talking about air ambulance, it will be available only in Black and Elite.  There will be a
capping of ₹5 lakh.  Up to some
assured ICC will be in Labad's Elevate plan.
Air ambulance add-on cover will be
available for another ₹5 lakh.  Select plan has an inbuilt feature of up to
₹5 lakh per policy year with add-on cover. Super
Star has an inbuilt feature of
No Claim Bonus in Ultimate Care Plan of Assured Care Health Insurance.
What does inbuilt No Claim Bonus
mean but if I talk about Reshore 3.0 then there is
no justification of No Claim Bonus there.  Nothing gets created
because time and noise are unlimited.  So no
claim bonus, restoration, all these benefits
or top-up everything gets lost.  When your
time limit becomes unlimited, then 20% will
go up to a maximum of Rs. 100. ICC's Elevate
plan will not reduce it and will be available
even in case of a claim.  50% yearly up to 100%
under Medicare Select plan of Tata AIG
and if you do not want to avail this no claim bonus
then your premium will be reduced by 1%.
50% Yearly Maximum 100
Superstar 50% Yearly Maximum 100
Ultimate Care No deductible
on claim.  Home care domiciliary treatment up to sum
assured is covered under all five policies.  Now we will
talk about pre-existing diseases, which are
diseases that already exist.  I am talking about other than 145.  I am
talking about the inbuilt features.  It
is 36 months old in Niva 3.0 and can be
reduced.
We can reduce this for 1 year and 2 years.
36 Months, 36 Months, 36 Months, 36 Months
is available in the remaining four policies.  Let's
talk about annual health checkup here.  There is an add on
cover.  Rashard could take The List at Ace in 3.0.  A
little extra premium will have to be paid.
And with add on covers you will get
5% of the sum assured up to ₹5000 on the policy year under Elevate plan
1%
of the sum assured up to ₹25,000 on the
policy year under Select plan 1% of the
sum assured up to ₹25,000 on the policy year under
Superstar plan cover with add ons
Annual health checkup will be covered
in Ultimate Care.  Alternative
treatment, which we call AYUSH
treatment, is covered up to sumshared in all the policies.
Now here
comes the matter of maternity.  It's a maternity event.  There
is no disease.  Comes into the life of youngsters.  It comes
into the lives of those who get married.
So this option
is not available in Rashord 3.0.  Not even with the addon.  It is
not even inbuilt.  10% of the basic
sum assured will be available after 2 years.  After
taking an add on cover in ICC LB's Elevate plan
and also in Select, it is available
10% of the sum assured maximum 1 lakh but
after two years it can be reduced to
500 and 1 lakh after 2
years Superstar not covered in Ultimate
Care plan Consumables are available
with add on in all the policies except Accept
Select plan, here you will get inbuilt consumables,
in Superstar only 68
items will be available as consumables.
In all other policies, all four lists will be covered
with add-on cover.  Wellness programs are also included
in all policies these days and
should be included.  Because now we all are health conscious.
Keep yourself healthy.   I
exercise, I go for a walk.  So
if you walk a certain number of steps per day,
you are tracked through
their app across all policies.  Here at Neevapa
you can get discounts up to 30%.
If you keep yourself healthy.
Same 30% will be there in Elevate.
Points will be earned here.
You can purchase a gift against that.  You will get
up to 20% discount on Medicare Select plan and up
to 30% discount with add-ons
under Ultimate Care.  One
option comes which is deductible.  Now it happens in almost all
policies.  It is a very good option.
If your premium is
increasing dramatically and you are healthy.
So you
can reduce your premium by using the deductible.  Deductible
means the amount you are choosing, which you will either
pay from your pocket or if
you have some other parallel source of insurance,
then you will have to pay from there.  iv) You can save a lot of premium by taking a deductible up to ₹
10,000 ₹20,000 ₹50,000 ₹1 2 3 4 lakh in Yashor 3.0.
This
option is not available in Elvet.  Options of Rs 10, 25, 500, 1
lakh are available in Mediar Select.
Deductible options will not be available in Superstar and Ultimate Care.
Let's complete the video.  But it will be
completed with premium.  Let us take
a look at the premiums, if it is a new plan then
what kind of premiums have been kept.   Will it
suit your pocket, will it fit your budget or
not?  So first of all I take
Neeva's Reshore 3.0.  Here I
will analyze it on two sides.  The
address is Delhi NCR.  Here the option is only unlimited.
And here also
I have taken the unlimited option of Elevate plan
because only then the comparison will be possible.  You will have to pay ₹46,492 for the
black variant.
If your age is 40 years then you can apply for Adult Two Kit
for Delhi NCR.  There the age
slab changes to 46 years.  Your premium at 46 years will be
₹58.77.
It is not very expensive because as per the
age and unlimited, it can be
said to be up to the mark.  ICamard tends to be
a bit more expensive.  Here you will have to pay ₹7139
for Unlimited Sum Assured for
Two Adult Two Kit for age 40 years.  At the same time,
if the age is 46 and the
family size is the same, then one will have to pay ₹84,579.
Now let's compare the remaining three plans
as they do
not have the option of unlimited sum assured.  So I have taken such a
reasonable sum assured which
you should have at least, cover of ₹25 lakh,
same family size, same age group,
same Delhi NCR address, at the
age of 40, Tata AIRG Medical
Select ₹25 lakh, ₹3434, very economical,
₹44933,
you will have to pay at the age of 46,
Superstar becomes a bit expensive,
₹4539,
you will have to pay for 40 years, ₹4631,
two adult to kid for 46 years, ₹25 lakh,
time, Delhi NCR address, ₹4182,
Ultimate Care for 40 years, ₹25 lakh,
time, two adult to kid, Delhi NCR and
₹757, at the age of
46, same family size and
age, ₹25 lakh, tax, Delhi NCR,
so these are all their premiums.
You have to see
what these premiums are saying to your pocket.  So
you have to choose your plan accordingly.  Now
what is the summary of these plans?
What is the conclusion?  So if I
talk about the fundamentals
of an insurance company, then obviously ICC LBA
comes number one here.  In claim settlement ratio
, in incurred claim ratio and
also in solvency.  But if we talk about premium,
you have many options.   If we
talk about unlimited then there is nothing better than Niva Book.
It
is the cheapest compared to all these plans because the
time there becomes unlimited.  Now this
choice is yours.  You have to see
what matters to you, what
holds value for you.
You should choose your plan accordingly.
Whatever questions you have related to these five plans, you
can ask me in my comment box.   I will
meet you in my next video.   Till then
Jai Hind Jai Bharat.